## JOERI NICOLAES

Spiltstraat 232, 1980 Zemst, Belgium - +32 476 443 772 - joerinicolaes@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/joeri-nicolaes-9371271/

## **Summary**

Joeri is a computer scientist focusing on computer vision tasks in the medical imaging domain. He is currently conducting research to apply deep learning techniques for detecting fractures in patient images.

Joeri is driven by pushing beyond boundaries and is passionate about learning along the way. He has a proactive, entrepreneurial mindset and completes his goals in a sustainable & timely manner.

Previously, Joeri acquired various technical, communication and managerial skills as IT architect and Professional Services leader. He has realized sales and delivery success taking numerous roles in various projects across EMEA.

# **Experience**

UCB Anderlecht, Belgium

## **Computer Scientist**

**November 2016 - Present** 

- Implementing a 3D Convolutional Neural Network prototype to locate and detect fractures in patient images
- Collaborating with academia experts in deep learning and medical image computing to learn and leverage state-of-the-art techniques

### **Senior Enterprise Architect**

November 2014 – October 2016

- Co-developed Hadoop architecture ingesting social media streams to gain patient insights
- Developed Enterprise Architecture framework to rationalize Analytics capabilities within UCB

Parking Plaza Zemst, Belgium

**Co-Founder** 

July 2016 - October 2017

- Founded start-up offering digital service allowing home users to rent their private parking place to visitors looking for a temporary parking spot
- Developed technical solution and marketed prototype for parkings near soccer stadium

## **Siemens Enterprise Communications / Unify**

Huizingen, Belgium

## **Head of Professional Services**

**April 2012 – October 2014** 

- Led the operations team for BeNeFraLux region delivering over €15m yearly in software and services projects across a growing customer base
- Led the sales and bid development process for all services engagement and proposals between €100k to €5m+, focused on driving services profit (as sold prices) to achieve gross margin targets of over 35%
- Transformed the Resource Management Office managing 80+ Services employees and improving the utilization achievement across the Services BU
- Led the cross-functional Cloud team (sales design & pricing, marketing and communication, delivery team) resulting in successful launch of a Public Cloud via Walloon telco provider

- Led the Healthcare program to standardize the Design Blueprint, initiate the sales & marketing campaign & develop growth in that industry, reporting to BeLux board
- Innovated the Professional Services strategy (regionalization of services, technology partner sourcing, innovation focus through customized development, service partner offering)

#### **Head of Consulting & Design**

## **November 2010 – April 2012**

- Managed 8 Belgian Solution Architects driving their competence, capacity & performance management
- Led sales and bid development for the extension of the Solvay Unified Communications infrastructure into a global solution reducing communication costs by 15%

**Solution Architect** 

June 2007 - October 2010

- Achieved senior Voice SIP & Networking (CCNP) integrator expertise after 1 year
- Achieved a successful go live as Solution Architect for Danish Government on a complex private cloud solution for over 40,000 users
- Coached junior professional services and presales team members

Altran Brussels, Belgium

#### Consultant

**September 2005 - June 2007** 

- Business Project Manager at Mobistar, part of France Telecom Group
- Led fixed and mobile voice project within time & budget for national railway provider NMBS/SNCB, leading 15+ virtual team and managing all customer communication at CxO level
- Coached several junior team members

#### **Education**

# Katholieke Universiteit Leuven (Catholic University of Leuven) Leuven, Belgium Doctoral Programme in Engineering Science September, 2018 - Present

- Promotor: Prof. Vandermeulen (ESAT/PSI)
- Title: End-to-end learning of intensity features and anatomical priors from 3D patient images

UC Berkeley California, US

## **Deep Reinforcement Learning Bootcamp**

August, 2017

- Two-day bootcamp with mix of lectures and hands-on sessions (Python)
- DeepRL foundations and state-of-the-art methods

Coursera Zemst, Belgium

## Machine Learning (Stanford University – Andrew Ng)

2014

• 10-weeks course introducing Machine Learning (algorithms theory + exercises in Octave)

RealAcad Brussels, Belgium

### **Venture Management Program**

2010

• 6-days Program to develop leadership and entrepreneurial skills

## **Vlerick Leuven-Gent Management School**

Blankenberge, Belgium

Creativity Class 2009

• Selected for 4-days Creativity and Innovation Class, part of winning team (Flecs)

# Katholieke Universiteit Leuven (Catholic University of Leuven) Leuven, Belgium Master in Engineering, specialization in Biomedical Techniques 2000-2005

- Master thesis and internship (Agfa Gevaert) in medical image processing software
- Graduated with Magna Cum Laude, top 5% in class

## **Additional Information**

- **Interests**: autodidact since 2010 on personal & team effectiveness through 7 Habits book study; tennis player; soccer coach U8 team of my oldest son
- Languages: native speaker of Dutch; fluent in English and French; notions of Spanish